Guide to the China Records Project Miscellaneous Personal Papers Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Papers of Individuals: H - M, Series II
  - Hunter, James A.
    - Brochures, booklets re. Tunghai University and Taiwan Livestock Research Institute, 1999 (Box 358, Folder 4)
  - Hunter, Maude (Mrs. James A.)
    Biog. info: ABCFM Peking, Paoting, Tunghsien (1919-1948)
    - Typescript memoir by Maude B. Hunter: "Nostalgia - I remember I remember" (Box 100, Folder 17-18)
    - Photographs and Chinese Art: "Livestock, vegetation and peoples" (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1948, 1960 (Box 247, Folder 2)
    - 3 photo albums documenting work of Hunters in Taiwan incl. re. Tunghai University and Sino-American Technical Cooperation Association, 1957-1961 (Box 247, Folder 3)
    - Tape recording, Tunghai University, Taipei, Taiwan, 1950-1955 (Box 247, Folder 4)
  - Huntington Family
    Biog. info: ACM Hankow, Ichang, Anking, Anhui (1895-1940): Daniel Trumbull Huntington was a bishop. Maria C. Huntington his mother; Virginia his wife
    - Photographs: People (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Letter from Daniel Trumbull Huntington primarily to Bobby (his brother), 1894-1902 (Box 102, Folder 2-4)
    - Correspondence: Letter from DTH to Sara, 1935-1936 (Box 102, Folder 5)
    - Typescript Material: "Recollections" by DTH, autobiographical writing re. his life upto ca. 1912, ca. 1948 (Box 102, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Letter from Maria C. Huntington to Clementine(Mrs. J.C), 1900 (Box 102, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Letters from Virginia Huntington (Mrs. Daniel T.) to Sara, 1935 (Box 102, Folder 8)
  - Huntley, Frank L.
    Biog. info: Son of medical missionary George Huntley
    - "Stories for Children - Mostly True but Some Made-up (Being the Memoirs of a Missionary Kid)", 1978 (Box 357, Folder 12)
  - Huntley, George A.
    American Baptist medical missionary based at Hanyang, Hankow
    - Photocopies of two annual reports of Hanyang Medical Mission, Hankow; article by Huntley "Revolutionary Experiences in Hankow", 1907, 1909, 1911 (Box 373, Folder 8)
  - Iverson, Lalla, MD
    Biog. info: 1919 Born in St. Matthews, S.C.; 1940 B.S. in Chemistry from Johns Hopkins University; 1943 Graduated from Johns Hopkins School of Medicine; 1948 Took job as head of the Department of Pathology of the Cheeloo College of Medicine in Jinan, Shandong; Dr. Iverson has spent a lifetime working in developing areas of Asia, including China, the Philippines and India. In 1952-1954, she spent a year as a visiting professor at the University of the Philippines, helping the university to restructure its Department of Pathology. From 1950-1960, Dr. Iverson was Senior Pathologist for the Armed Forces Institute of Pathology in Washington, D.C. In 1960, she traveled to India, where she started a medical system specifically designed for the country.
    - Typescript material: Biographical Summary of Lalla Iverson incl. letters re. her death, 1988-1989 (Box 313, Folder 1)
    - Xeroxed copies: Cheeloo Medical College: Letters from students and staff re. events of 1949 and turnover, 1949, 1989 (Box 313, Folder 2)
    - Xeroxed copies of the evacuation of Cheloo Medical College, 1948 (Box 313, Folder 3)
    - Xeroxed copies re. case files of 2 students Chi Ming and Liao Hsiang Ping by Lalla Iverson, 1948 (Box 313, Folder 4)
    - Typescript list of students at Cheloo Medical College in Tsinan, Shantung incl. photo of students and faculty, opening day, 1948-1949 (Box 313, Folder 5)
    - Typescript ms.: Chapter one of "China and Change" by Lalla Iverson, former Director of Pathology Dept. at Cheloo Medical College in Tsinan, Shantung (Box 313, Folder 6)
  - Jackson, Richard and Dorothy
    ABCFM, Shaowu, Fukien
    - 1 circular letter, 1947 (Box 376, Folder 25)
  - Jarvis, Anna Moffett (Mrs. Bruce W.)*
    Biog. info: MEFB Peking, Foochow (1920-1949)?
    - Photographs re. laying of the cornerstone - Union Christian Hospital, Foochow (W.F. Pierce Memorial), the Funeral of Sun Yat-Sen, buildings looted and burned in July 1927, Peking Summer palace, Ming Deh School, Nanking, etc., 1927, 1929, 1930, 1937 (Box 103, Folder 1)
    - Typescript compilation of letters: "Letters from China 1920-1949" (Box 103, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Circular letters, 1937-1939, 1942-1943 (Box 103, Folder 3-5)
    - Typescript reports: "Report from Japan" by M. Searle Bates (1937), "Toward an Understanding of China" by M. Searle Bates (1937 Jul), "Review of the First Month" by Minnie Vautrin (1938 Jan), "Preliminary Report of Christian Work in Nanking - Winter 1937" by M.S. Bates and W.P. Mills (1938 Feb), "Notes on the Present Situation" (1938 Mar 21), "Pseudo-economic Notes from Nanking" (1938 Mar 31), "Sharing 'the Abundant Life' in a Refugee Camp" by Minnie Vautrin (1938 Apr 28), "Faculty Report of Nanking Theological Seminary 1937-1938" by Pres. Handel Lee, "Report of Extension Services in Shanghai" (Nanking Theol. Sem.) by P.F. Price, "Showchow Station REport for 1938-1939" by Mabel Steele Jones (1939 May 5), "Report re. Showchow, anhwei by Mabel Jones", "Personal Report - April 1941-August 1942" by Anna E. Moffett, 1937, 1938, 1941, 1942 (Box 103, Folder 6)
    - Chinese Language Material: Invitations, Eulogy, Memorial Booklet, re. Buddhism (Box 103, Folder 7)
  - Jett, Wenona Wilson (Mrs. Harry C.)
    Biog. info: EPM Fukien Prov. (1920-1950)
    - Photographs: General Conference in Atlantic city, N.J., Hardy Training School incl. Junior High, Primary school and Kindergarten; Money, 1922, 1932 (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - Photographs of Mr. Harry Carmichael Jett and his wife Mrs. Wenona Wilson Jett and other scenes (Box 104, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Letters from Wenona Jett to family, 1920-1932 (Box 104, Folder 3-4)
    - Correspondence: Letters from Wenona to family and friends, 1933-1971 (Box 104, Folder 5-11)
    - Typescript report: Yung-Te-Ta Report, 1946-1950 (Box 104, Folder 12)
    - Typescript report: "One year at Christ Hospital", Cooles Calling: Conf. and related reports", "Progress report from Trinity Theological College, Singapore", "Report of Christ Hospital and its Clinics for the year 1962", 1951-1963 (Box 104, Folder 13)
    - Newsletters, 1934-1967 (Box 104, Folder 14)
    - Printed Material: "China has Changed her mind", "Women's World Day of Prayer", 1951 (Box 104, Folder 15)
    - Chinese Language Material (Box 104, Folder 16)
    - Cards, 1913-1939, 1970 (Box 104, Folder 17)
    - Typescript Material: "The Rev. Harry Carmichael Jett" memorial by John Gowdy (Box 104, Folder 18)
    - 3 pieces of fabric (Box 261, Folder 1)
  - Johannaber, Charles F.
    Biog. info: MEFB Kiukiang, Kiangsi, Shanghai (1916-1949)
    - Typewritten Material re. Christian Religious Education: "R.E. 92 Curriculum Group - Spring 1930", "Kuling Religious Education Conference", Religious Education - 1932", "Minutes of R.E. Committee June '35'", "Program of C.E. for Middle School youth", "C.E. 1936", "Local Training program - 1936, "Young People's Group - 1937", Young People's program - 1938-1942", 1930-1942 (Box 105, Folder 1-8)
    - Pamphlets: Chinese Language Material, 1936-1937 (Box 105, Folder 9)
    - Typewritten Material: "Kiangsi Annual Conference Evangelism 1933-1936" (Box 105, Folder 10)
    - Typewritten Material: "Soviet Russia and the Chinese Revolution China Information", 1938, 1939 (Box 105, Folder 11)
    - Typewritten Material: "New Plan for Nast - Gamble Church, 1936 (Box 105, Folder 12)
    - Typescript Material: "Illustrated Lecture on Methodist Episcopal Church Mission work in Kiangsi Province, China, Methodist Help to Remake Kiangsi by CFJ, 1937 (Box 105, Folder 13)
    - Printed Material: "Rural Church Survey" The Lichwan Service Center, 1937 (Box 105, Folder 14)
    - Typewritten Material: "Unit on the Faculty" (Box 105, Folder 15)
    - Published Material by CFJ: incl. "The Old Testament Its Use, Origin, and Message", "New Life Centers in Rural Kiangsi" (Special Bulletin), 1936, 1937 (Box 105, Folder 16)
    - Typewritten interview: "Students' Problems", 1937 (Box 105, Folder 17)
    - Typewritten and handwritten material: "Kiukiang, China William Nast Academy Religious Work in the School", 1933-1936 (Box 105, Folder 18)
    - Misc: "Explanatory material" (Box 105, Folder 19)
    - Clippings: "Board-meeting minutes etc. of The Christian Rural Project in Shanghai found in CFJ's files, 1934-1937 (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - Records: Class of 1937 (Box 106, Folder 2-5)
  - Jones, Alfred George
    Biog. info: BMS (1876-1905)
    - Two photograph albums documenting British missionaries and missionary work in Shantung and Shansi provinces, incl. residence destroyed by Boxers and family killed in Boxer uprising., ca. 1876-1905 (Box 325)
  - Jones, Clara
    Biog. info: LUM Fancheng, Hup.
    - Printed Articles by Clara Jones: "SOS", "Jesus is Christmas", "China's Youth is on the March", "Tribute to Olive Hodnefield", "This is the Day", "Out of Doubt into Faith", "These Ways led to God", "Our Church", "Chinese Kitchen God Returns", "War at the Front in China", "Through Mud from Peking to Kioshan", "Adds More Wives", etc., 1940-1971 (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - Typescript ms: Unpublished dissertation of Clara Jones: "The Cross in Conquest Over China", 1958 (Box 107, Folder 2)
  - Jones, Lora Malvina (Zhou En-ying)
    Biog. info: Born in 1914 and abandoned, she was adopted by American missionary Edith Frances Jones. Graduated from Seattle Pacific University in 1943 then returned to China. Under the Communists she was accused of being a CIA agent was imprisoned for 20 years. After her release in 1979 she taught English at Lanzhou University and was an active member of the pastoral team of Lanzhou Christian Church.
    - Correspondence: Letters to friends, 1980-1997, 2000 (Box 327, Folder 1-9)
    - Correspondence: Letters to family, 1998-1999, n.d. (Box 327, Folder 10-11)
    - Correspondence: Uncertain dates and fragments (Box 327, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: Other letters to Lora John Schlosser, 1981-2002 (Box 327, Folder 12-14)
    - Correspondence: Letters of others, 1989, 2002 (Box 327, Folder 15-18)
    - Collected material: Testimonies, misc. (Box 327, Folder 19)
    - Biographical information, 1980 (Box 327, Folder 20)
  - Jones, Tracey K.*
    Biog. info: YMCA; MEFB Canton (1917-1928)
    - Correspondence: Primarily from Canton, 1922-1927 (Box 107, Folder 3-21)
    - Typescript and Chinese documents: "Teacher's information, Purity Campaign: Lessons I - V", "The Canton Purity Campaign" by TKJ (1922 Apr), "The Girl Slavery System of Canton" by TKJ (1922), Statement by girl slave, Ying Sai and photograph, Slave contract (in Chinese and translation), Poster in opposition of female slavery (1922 Apr), "Canton" by TKJ (1926), "Economic Tendencies and Red Hopes in China", 1922-1926 (Box 107, Folder 22-25)
    - Pamphlet: "Will China Have a Red Revolution?" by Arthur Boggess (TKJ), 1925 (Box 107, Folder 26)
  - Judd, Walter H. (M.D.)
    Biog. info: ABCFM Shaowu
    - Correspondence: Letters from Walter H. Judd, 1927, 1931, 1938 (Box 107, Folder 27-29)
  - Judson, J. H. and Jennie (Filley)
    Biog. info: PN Hangchow, Chekiang (1879-1923) Boarding and trade school which became Hangchow Xn. Coll., Shanghai (1923-1924)
    - Typescript Material: "Reminiscences of J.H. Judson (1852-1925), Hangchow (1880-1925) (Box 107, Folder 30)
  - Kavooghian, Victoria
    Biog. info: YM (1931-1935)
    - Photographs: Students of Hunan-Yale Hospital Training School for Nurses, Hsiang Ya Hospital, etc., 1934-1935 (Box 108, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1933-1935 (Box 108, Folder 2)
    - Pamphlet: "Quaint Korea" How Much it costs to see Peiping (Peking) (Box 108, Folder 3)
    - Scroll (Box 108, Folder 4)
  - Kelker, Fred
    Kelker and his wife Harrisburg, Pennsylvania were laypeople in the Dutch Reformed Church who undertook at world tour in 1909-1910 and visited Reformed missions in China and Japan.
    - Handwritten diary describing trip to China and Japan with laid in newspaper clippings, 1909-1910 (Box 385, Folder 9)
  - Kepler, Raymond F.
    Biog. info: PN Siangtan, Hengyang, Hangchow, Changsha (1930-1948)
    - Typescript Material: Documents from 5th General Assembly C.C.C, 1948 (Box 107, Folder 31)
    - Writings: Envelope with Chinese writing, issue of "The Church", 1948; "Directory of Protestant Missions in China - 1940", 1940, 1948 (Box 107, Folder 32)
    - Pamphlets: Chinese Language Material, 1947-1948 (Box 107, Folder 33-34)
  - Kiang Wen-Han (Jiang Wenhan)
    Worked for Chinese YMCA
    - Typescript report describes visit to Hangchow with Bengt Hoffman to survey Christian student work in the area, 1948 (Box 376, Folder 26)
  - Killie, Charles and Louise
    American Presbyterian missionaries stationed at Shantung and Peking Missions 1889-1912
    - Circular letter written by Louise Killie from Ichowfu, 1891 (Box 385, Folder 11)
    - Four photographs, including Mrs. Killie in horse drawn cart, Dr. Hunter in native dress at Chinese hotel, girls at Tungchow Girls School, Pebbly Beach at Tungchowfu, circa 1890s (Box 385, Folder 12)
  - Kinnear, H. W., M.D.
    ABCFM, Foochow
    - Circular letter from Foochow Missionary Hospital, 1913 (Box 309, Folder system_indicator_410a99705bfe635c820f3ef0edcda436)
  - Kintner, Helen
    ABCFM: Appointed 1930, nurse assigned to Tungchow Hospital, Tunghsien, near Peking
    - Compilation of her letters written home to family, 1930-1934 (Box 357, Folder 13-14)
  - Kirk, Florence
    For Florence Kirk correspondence, see University of Regina online resource: Florence A. Kirk: Letters from China, 1932-1950.
    Biog. info: Taught at Ginling College, Nanking
    - Photographs: Ginling College faculty, Ginling class 1934-1950, Vacation, relocation of Ginling College to Chengtu, Scenes of Nanking, refugee camp at Ginling, group photos in China, etc., 1933-1987 (Box 314, Folder 1-8)
  - Kirkpatrick, Paul Harmon
    Kirkpatrick (1894-1992) taught at Hangchow Christian College 1916-1918. He later continued his education and was a professor at Stanford University 1931-1958.
    - Booklet compiled by Kirkpatrick family: "Letters Home - An Account of Experiences in Hangchow, China 1916-1918" (Box 374, Folder 1)
  - Knickerbocker, Edgar F.*
    Biog. info: CIM, PN: Ningpo, Chekiang Province, 1893-1901, 1909-1915
    - Bound notebook: Handwritten autobiography of EFK (Box 258, Folder 1)
    - Diaries, primarily in Ningpo, 1909-1916 (Box 258, Folder 2-9)
    - Diaries, 1916-1927 (Box 259, Folder 1-6)
  - Koo, T.Z. (Gu Ziren)
    Koo was associate general secretary and student executive secretary of the Chinese YMCA National Committee from 1919 to 1930. From 1929 to 1934 he was vice-chairman of the World's Student Christian Federation and from 1934 to 1947 its general secretary.
    - Circular letter, including regarding political situation in China, 1932 (Box 309, Folder 2)
  - Kreps, Esther E.
    Biog. info: CBM Liaochow, Sha. (L.1926-L.1927)
    - Correspondence: Letter from EEK to sister and family, 1926 (Box 109, Folder 1)
    - Writings of EEK: "Scenes in Everyday Life in China", "Mission Hospital and War at Liao", "The Nursing Profession in China", "Impressions of Chinese Thinking", 1926-1927 (Box 109, Folder 2)
    - Writings of Nettie Mabelle Senger: "Friendships Evangelistic Work Under a Different Name", "Present Day China and Christianity", "Village Evangelism: The Field Work and Aim of the Evangelist", "Christianity and Buddhist China", "Village Evangelism: Teaching Religion in the Villages", 1926- (Box 109, Folder 3)
    - Typed and handwritten Material incl. "The present Crisis in Christian Education" by Hu Shih, "The Development of the Logical Method in Ancient China" by Hu Shih, "Notes from Chu Hsi and his Masters" by J.P. Bruce, etc., 1926-1927, 1944, 1949 (Box 109, Folder 4)
  - Krueger, John F.
    Biog. info: LUM Tsingtao, Sung. (L.1926-L.1928)
    - Writing by John F. Krueger: "On a Mule Trip into the Interior of Shantung", 1926 (Box 109, Folder 5)
  - Kunkle, J. Stewart Kunkle, Julia Mitchell (Mrs. J. Stewart)
    Biog. info: PN Linchow, Canton (L.1916-L.1936)
    - Writings, 1845-1889 (Box 107, Folder 35-43)
    - Reports: "Annual report, 1845", "Report on the first phase: Lingnan University Planning Survey" (Box 107, Folder 44-45)
    - Typescript Material: "History of the Medical Work of Lingnan University" by William W. Cadbury (Box 107, Folder 46)
    - Typed Material: Introduction concerning Mrs. Stewart Kunkle, 1966 (Box 107, Folder 47)
  - Lanphear, B. Woodward
    Lanphear was an American Episcopal missionary based in Wuhu.
    - Seven personal letters to Ruth Dunsford and five circular letters describe Lanphear's educational work in Wuhu amidst political disruption and civil war, forced evacuation, death of his wife Carolyn, return to U.S. with their child, 1926-1928 (Box 376, Folder 7)
  - Lawson, Thyra (Sister)
    Biog. info: Aug. Hsuchang, Hunan (1912-c.1954)
    - Handwritten ms: Biographical Information by Thyra Lawson, 1971 (Box 110, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Letters primarily to family, 1913-1940s (Box 110, Folder 2-18)
    - Correspondence: Letters primarily to family, 1950s (Box 111, Folder 1-5)
    - Correspondence: Letters to Thyra Lawson primarily from her students, 1960s, 1970 (Box 111, Folder 6-8)
    - Correspondence: Greeting cards, post cards, printed materials, 1919, 1934-1971 (Box 111, Folder 9)
    - Diaries, 1940-1944, 1946-1951, 1951-1954 (Box 111, Folder 10)
    - Printed Material and writings incl. "Experiences in China" By Thyra Lawson, 1949-1969, 1973 (Box 111, Folder 11)
  - Lee, Lucy Chaplin (Mrs. Edmund)*
    Biog. info: ACM Anking (1902-1927)
    - Printed booklet - "An American Sojourn in China - Family Memories" by Lucy Chaplin Lee, 1968 (Box 113, Folder 1)
    - Diary: "The Missionaries' Anglo-Chinese Diary for 1905" (Box 113, Folder 2)
  - Lee, Thomas*
    Biog. info: LUM, 1924-1953, primarily in Honan until 1949 May and in Hong Kong, 1949 May - 1953 Feb.
    - Papers consist of more than 85 photocopies of mimeographed circular letters. These substantive letters (some ten or more pages) date from 1947 until 1958 and provide valuable detailed information about the Church in China in the years leading up to and following the Communist takeover. Lee had extensive correspondence with Chinese and Western individuals in China while he was working in Hong Kong and received numerous Christian periodicals from China, from which he quotes in his circular letters. He provides specific information des- cribing the work of missionaries who remained in China following the Communist takeover and regarding the status of schools and hospitals in the interior. He provides information about Church activities and conferences in China such as the Enlarged Council of the Lutheran Church in China meeting in January, 1951 and the Peking Christian Conference of April, 1951 where the Accusation Movement was inaugurated. These letters are written from a clearly anti-Communist stance. They provide extensive information regarding the development of the Three Self Movement in China., 1947-1956 (Box 113, Folder 3-8)
  - Leete, William R.
    - 3 circular letters from Nanking, 1947-1948 (Box 309, Folder 3)
  - Leger, Samuel Howard
    Biog. info: ABCFM Foochow, Peking Fukien Xn. Univ. (1917-1944)
    - Correspondence, 1917- 1939 (Box 114, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence related to unpublished mss. "The Christian Religion in Modern China", 1932 (Box 114, Folder 2)
    - Typescript report by SHL: "Annual reports 1921, 1933"; "The Successes and Failures of the Devolution Process in the Mid. Fukien and North Fukien Synods", 1921-1933, 1927-1944 (Box 114, Folder 3)
    - Published articles by SHL: "Family Life in China", "China Chaos and Hope" (Box 114, Folder 4)
    - Typescript articles by SHL: "The Concept of Institutionalization", "Institutionalized Culture Pattern", "Macro-analysis in the Social Sciences", "Short Wave Radio in Education", "The Social Science and World Peace", "Social Theory and Social Problems", "Scientific Studies in the Social Sciences", "Suggestions for a program for General Education", "Twelve Implications of Comparative Sociology" (Box 114, Folder 5)
    - Typescript mss. (Unpublished): "The Christian Religion in Modern China", 1932 (Box 114, Folder 6)
    - Typescript mss. (Unfinished book): "National Institutional System", 1956 (Box 114, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous mss. related to China by SHL: "China and the Post-War World", "Chinese Studies on the Pacific Coast", "China - World Melting Pot", "The Contributions of Chinese Culture to World Community", "Three Builders of Modern China", "Three Kinds of Power in Eastern Asia" (Box 114, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous mss. by SHL: "Action to Match our Faith", "Congregationalism, Democracy and Individualism", "Should Foreign Missionaries Return Home at Fifty?", "The Quest for peace through World Organisations", "Anti-slavery or Pro-Union - 1860 and 1948", "Lincoln and the Present World Crisis", "Cultural Problems of one World" (Box 114, Folder 9)
    - Typed term papers by SHL: "Outline of a System of Sociology", "The Rural Community - A Psycho-functional Societary Organism", 1940 (Box 114, Folder 10)
    - Printed Material: "The National Christian Council" by J.H.Oldham, "Program Annual Meeting Foochow Congregational Church 1926", 1922, 1926 (Box 114, Folder 11)
    - Typescript Material: Autobiographical Sketch of SHL (Box 114, Folder 12)
    - Typewritten Material (Fragments): pp.108-120 (Box 114, Folder 13)
  - LeTourneau, Marie and Sarah (Mrs. Marie L. Olsen)
    Biog. info: CMML Shang Pu Teo, Shantung (1921-L.1927)
    - Photographs of their work and postcards of Tingtao; 9pp. Missionary talk, 1921-1935 (Box 119, Folder 1)
  - Lewis, Neil and Alice
    Biog. info: Alice Hay Lewis (1900-2001) and Neil Huntington Lewis (1895-1980) were graduates of Oberlin College and Neil received a medical degree from Western Reserve. They went to China in 1925 as ABCFM missionaries, stationed at the American Board Hospital, Foochow. They returned to the U.S. in 1932, expecting to return after their furlough, but their support was withdrawn due to the Depression. Neil practiced medicine in California from 1933.
    - Compilation of family correspondence: including regarding departure to China, supplies taken, river trip to Foochow, language study, trips to Ingtai, Kuliang, Pagoda Anchorage, birth of daughter Grace Luana, home robbed by soldiers (1927), difficulties at the hospital, political unrest, move to Ingtai, birth of son Philip, summers at Kuliang, Japanese attack, return to Foochow, 1923-1932 (Box 361, Folder 1)
    - Compilation of family corresopndence: including regarding reunion with Neil's parents in Shanghai, journey to U.S., Neil's studies at Columbia, time at Auburndale, MA, mission reports and letters to friends, decision of ABCFM that family should not return to China due to financial situation, move to California, birth of daughter Emily., 1932-1945 (Box 361, Folder 2)
    - Original format correspondence, 1923 - 1930 July (Box 379, Folder 1-20)
    - Original format correspondence, 1930 October - 1932 June (Box 380, Folder 1-5)
    - Circular letters of Lewises, 1925(?)-1933 (Box 361, Folder 3)
    - Letters to/from others, including Cushing, Gebhart, Gillette, Kinnear, Mott, Rawlinson (Box 361, Folder 4)
    - Writings and notes, including "The Elder Missionary at Dai-Vong", "The Hospital Gate Keeper", "Man Tortured by Bandits" (Box 361, Folder 5)
    - Writings and notes, including "Sharp Peak", "A Country Tour", "Dreams of a Country Doctor", "Chinese Education and Literature" (Box 361, Folder 6)
    - Writings and notes, including "Farmlife", "Hospital Work in China" (Box 361, Folder 7)